

Senior Front End Developer

Profile -

Meticulous web developer with over 5 years of front end experience and passion for responsive website design and a firm believer in the mobile-first approach. Implemented new responsive website approach which increased mobile traffic by 30%.

Contact ·

- Bhuigar, Fatullah
- □ nazmuldipu@gmail.com
- **→** +880 1912 239643
- nazmul.monerbari.com
- in nazmuldipu
- nazmuldipu nazmuldipu

Languages -

English (Professional) German (B2)

Bengali (native)



- Interests -

- Travelling
- Photography

Education

Master of Science in Information Technology

University of Stuttgart, Germany. October 2010 - May 2013 Specialization in embedded Systems. Also, known Industrial Automation, Distributed Programming.

Bachelor of Science in Electrical and Electronics Engineering (EEE)

United International University, Dhaka, June 2006 - September 2009 Major: Electronics

Experience

Senior Front-end Developer

REFORMED TECH, Dhaka. June 2021 - Present

As a Senior Front End Developer, the primary responsibilities for this position include:

- Build modern client-side web applications using cutting edge technologies.
- Work seamlessly with the rest of the development team (e.g. back-end front-end developers)
- Work in an agile environment and Iterate quickly based on customer and internal feedback.
- Participating in design discussions, helping to decide company's best ways of building new features
- Mentor others in my areas of expertise.

Software Developer

UNOLO TECHNOLOGY LIMITED, Dhaka. March 2019 - May 2021

- As a full-stack software developer my responsibilities are Design, build, and maintain efficient, reusable, and reliable Java code for back-end and Angular code for front-end. Ensure the best possible performance, quality, and responsiveness of the applications. Identify bottlenecks and bugs, and devise solutions to these problems. Help maintain code quality, organisation, and automation.
- \bullet Analyzed systems flow, data usage, and work processes; investigated 100% of problem areas
- Developed and executed 200+ test procedures for software components
- Developed code following common security practices and development design patterns
- Analyzed 30+ user requirements to derive technical software design and performance requirements

Software Developer

MONERBARI TECHNOLOGY LIMITED, Dhaka. February 2017 – January 2019

As software, my main tasks are developing and implementing feature requirements for the Angular, REST API architecture, testing and debug backend.

Lecturer (PT)

United International University (UIU), Dhaka, September 2014 to January 2017

As a lecturer, I have attended structured programming language courses (Theory and Laboratory).

★ Skills

